Andrew Samuel

Sugar Land, TX | (832)-433-5160 | <u>samueltandrew@gmail.com</u> <u>GitHub</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

Summary

Self-motivated student pursuing a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science from University of Houston-Downtown. I am extremely passionate about the tech industry and I look forward to using my expertise gained from projects and course experience to fine-tune my skills and grow into a bigger asset working towards technological innovation.

Skills

Programming: Python, Java, C++, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and C

Database: Microsoft SQL Server and MySQL

IDE/Design: Spyder, NetBeans, Visual Studio, MySQL Workbench, XCode, Microsoft SQL

Server, and Android Studio

Software: Microsoft Office (MS), Google Drive, GitHub

Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows and MAC OS X

Education

University of Houston-Downtown, Houston, TX

December 2020

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Honors: Deans List-(Fall 2019, Spring 2019, Spring 2020)

<u>Relevant Coursework</u>: Database Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Human-Computer Interactions, Software Engineering, Operating Systems, Web Programming, and Object-Oriented Programming

Projects

Documentation/Debugger/Design

July 2020 – August 2020

University of Houston-Downtown, Houston, TX

• Cooperated within a group of 4 to create a satirical Android app that exhibits in an exaggerated fashion what IT developers go through to keep the growing number of technological devices working on a daily basis. [Inspired by "The IT Crowd"]

Co-Developer/Debugger

October 2019 - November 2019

University of Houston-Downtown, Houston, TX

• Facilitated within a group of 5 to create a Student Management System using Java and MySQL that can access and manipulate student records much like Blackboard or Canvas.

Debugger December 2018

University of Houston-Downtown, Houston, TX

• Assessed cost effective ways to span a weighted graph tree with given coordinates using "Prims Algorithm" in a group of 5 using Python.

Experience

Co-Developer

February 2020 - May 2020

Lonestar College Montgomery Campus, Montgomery, TX

- Collaborated with a group of 3 to create a database for a bio-log to hold biology records of different research sites and campuses to be used in campus-wide biology research.
- Utilized MySQL for the back-end database development and Visual Basic for the front-end user interface

Financial Intern (Paid)

May 2016 - July 2016

Prognosis Innovation. Houston, TX

• Recognized by Comptroller for skill to find and organize files used to expedite company audit